Guide to the Max Shachtman Papers TAM.103
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series III: Correspondence (microfilmed)
  - Part A: Individuals
    - Strickland, Donald (Ph.D. student), 1961 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Suall, Bert (SP) - Mississippi Democratic Party campaign, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Suall, Irwin (SP leader), 1960, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Survey (W. Laquer, editor) British journal of Soviet studies, (see also: Box 40/2), 1961-1962 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Tabachnik, Manny, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Tang, Peter S. H. (Author of Communist China Today), 1964 (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Thomas, Norman (Socialist Party leader) - on Lenin-ism; SP, 1957-1966 (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - Trachtenberg, Beverly (Widow of Ely, socialist), 1960 (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Tussing, Arlon (ISL, SPer) - Cuban question; Japan SP, 1957-1963 (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - University of Illinois - Inst. of Communications Research (see also: Box 38/6), 1965 (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - Vereeeken, G. (Belgian socialist), 1952 (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - Volkov " Estaban (Trotsky's grandson and heir), 1968-1969 (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - Wang, m. Y. - China, 1951-1953 (Box 31, Folder 38)
    - Weber, Jack (WP) - Stalin's crimes; The Nation, 1947-1962 (Box 31, Folder 39)
    - Weingarten, Adolph (German refugee) - letter to A.W. from Karl Retzlaw 4/4/64; historical resources, 1965-1968 (Box 31, Folder 40)
    - Weinrib, Max (ISL,SP) - MS's personal activities: work on history of Communist International; sound system; SP, 1952-1969 (Box 31, Folder 41-43)
    - Weir, Stanley (ISL, SP) - Robertson, Jim-ISL; "subversive activities" case, 1953-1961 (Box 31, Folder 44)
    - Whitcomb, John M. (Researcher) - Trotsky's stay in U.S., 1963-1964 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      Microfilm Reel Number 41
    - Widick, B.J. (Jack, Detroit socialist, writer) - defense of the Soviet Union, 1956-1957, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Wilson, Dick (SP, Ann Arbor) - speaking, 1961-1963 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Wittfogel, Karl A. (Socialist scholar) - Germany, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Wolfe, Bertram (Historian, Hoover Institute), 1968 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Wollod, Alex (SP, Philadelphia), 1961, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Wuertzel, Herb (a.k.a. Mason - Socialist in Mexico), 1951, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Zatinsky, Milton (SP, Washington D.C.), 1961 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - PART B: BY COUNTRY, INCLUDING NATIONALS-IN-EXILE
    - Argentina, 1938-1939 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Ceylon, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Cuba, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - France, including Spanish comrades, 1945-1950 (Box 32, Folder 12-13)
    - Germany, Socialists in exile (1943), condition of movement, 1943-1949 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Great Britain (and N. Ireland) Socialists; elections, 1948-1962 (Box 32, Folder 15-16 [one folder])
    - Holland, undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - India (see also: Box 30/10), undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Italy, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Japan, undated (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Lebanon and Syria, undated (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Mexico, undated (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Peru, undated (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Poland, 1940s (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Scandinavia, undated (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Spain, undated (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - U.S. Officials (overseas and DC -- See also: folders 31,39), undated (Box 32, Folder 27)
      Microfilm Reel Number 42
    - International Contacts: correspondence and notes, 1917-1919, 1936-1941 (Box 32, Folder 28-29)
  - PART C: BY TOPIC
    - Non-political business correspondence, undated (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Passport case - ACLU, 1953-1954 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Personal correspondence (family and friends - no last names), undated (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - Requests from archives and libraries (for archival papers, oral history ... ), undated (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Requests to bookstores and publishers for MS's research, undated (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Requests for reproduction rights and information on Trotsky (MS as agent), undated (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Requests from MS re: research and publications, undated (Box 32, Folder 36-37)
    - Speaking engagements - invitations to speak, 1948-1972 (Box 32, Folder 38)
    - "Subversive list" correspondence, 1948-1960 (Box 32, Folder 39)
  - PART D: BY PUBLISHER
    - Dell Publishing Co., 1961-1963 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      Microfilm Reel Number 43
    - Donald Press: Correspondence re-distribution of the Bureaucratic Rev. (see also: Box 29/12), undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Doubleday Publishers, 1957-1969 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Greenwood Reprint Corp., undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Grosset - Dunlap, 1959-1968 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Harvard University Library, 1940-1963 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
    - Harvard University Press, 1948-1955 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Harvard University Press - Thomas J. Wilson - editor, 1956-1958 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Harvard University Press, 1958-1962 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - International Editors - Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1960-1962 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - International Inst. Voor Sociale Geschiedenis, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Macmillan-Freepress - to have published MS's history of CI, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Random House Publishers - Trotsky's literary rights, undated (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Simon and Schuster Publishers - Trotsky's literary rights, 1957-1967 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Sugar Editore - Trotsky's literary rights, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - University of Michigan Press (see also: Series IV), 1957-1970 (Box 33, Folder 17-20)
      Microfilm Reel Number 44
    - U-M Press - Royalty Reports, undated (Box 33, Folder 21)
    - Verlag Herder - encyclopedic dictionary, 1964-1968 (Box 33, Folder 22)
- Series IV: Writings and topical files (partially microfilmed)
  - PART A: POLITICAL AFFAIRS - BY COUNTRY OR REGION - NOT U.S. (not microfilmed)
    - Algeria - in French, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Asia - clippings, articles, 1949, 1950s-1960s (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Austria political prisoners, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Ceylon publications, 1967 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Cuba - clippings, ads, pamphlets, 1958-1959 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Europe - articles, news clippings, 1930s (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - France - French leaflets and on Nationalization of banks, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - France - Contre Les Deux Blocs, Pour Le Socialisme, 1914, 1939 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Germany - anti-Liebknechts cartoon, ca.1910s (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Germany - from the Illustrierte Geschichte der Deutschen Revolution, ca.1929 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Germany - from Sekretariat der UAPD, Oct 10, 1952 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Germany - see also Series V, Hitler's Rise to Power, 1930s-1950s (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Hungary - Revolution (Scope magazine,1967) (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - India - articles, 1951-1956 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Ireland news article, 1921 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Israel American Jewish Committee, 1967, 1930s-1950s (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - Italy - news clippings (CP), 1939 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - Japan - Zengekium (Japan) appeal to International Anti-War Student Conference in Tokyo, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - Middle East - bulletins by Youth Committee for Peace and Democracy, 1930s-1970s (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - Letter from Paris, Jun 8, 1929 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - Poland news clippings (CP), 1930s-1950s (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - Rmania news clippings, 1940s-1950s (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Soviet Union - news clippings, book reviews, 1920s-1960s (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Soviet Union - World Press of 1944 (in German), undated (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Vietnam - letters, articles, news clippings, pamphlets, maps (Negotiations Now, Henry Kissinger), 1950s-1960s (Box 34, Folder 25-27)
    - Vietnam - letters, articles, newsletter, pamphlet, petitions, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 1-3)
    - Ludwik Hass - letter, 1920-1966 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Rosa Luxemburg - book review, letter, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Marx - news clippings, article, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Vannie B. Montana - article from La Parola de Popolo, 1930 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Soblen - article, 1929-1933 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Solzhenitsyn, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Stalin - clippings, articles, 1904-1950s (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Tresca - memorandum, 1930s (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Trotsky - articles about, 1911-1920s (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Trotsky - articles about, 1937 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Trotsky - articles by, 1904-1939 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Anti-Communism - article, undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Anti-War - articles, 1939, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - "Democrats No Longer a Majority: Harris" NY Post, Feb 2, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Leninism - article, 1916-1920 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Neuer Vormarts - social democratic weekly, Jul 16, 1933 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Peace - brochures, 1940s-1950s (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Political., Ethnic and Economic Map of Balkans (in French), undated (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - PART B: POLITICAL AFFAIRS - UNITED STATES - AMERICAN GROUPS (not microfilmed)
    - American Forum - conference, Communist Party, A.J. Muste (letters, pamphlets, articles), 1956-1960 (Box 35, Folder 22-24)
    - American groups - news clippings, 1901-1940s (Box 35, Folder 25)
    - American Jewish Committee - What is Extremism?, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Preamble to Constitution of American Legion, 1919 (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Commonwealth Congress - Provisional constitution, undated (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Communist Party - American leaflets, 1930s-1950s (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - CP Bulletins, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Communist Party - Mike Gold Daily World Column, Jan 28, 1938 (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - The Stalin-Hitler Pact - (CP?)' "It's Good for the Jews", 1929, 1939 (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - Independent - Socialist Ticket, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - League for Industrial Democracy' letters, memorandmn, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 34)
    - National Conference for New Politics' letters, listing, proposal, 1968 (Box 35, Folder 35)
    - New Committee for Publications Report' Issue #57, Nov 24, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 36)
    - Peace and Freedom - open letter, newsletter, 1961-1962 (Box 35, Folder 37)
    - Peace and Freedom and other left-wing groupings, 1967-1968 (Box 35, Folder 38)
    - A. Philip Randolph Institute - Freedom Budget, 1966-1975 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Polish Jewish Bund in USA - photo, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - SANE - bulletin, article, 1960s (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Socialist Union Party, 1941 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Workers Defense League, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Young People's Socialist League - articles by Alex Garber, Myrna Culbreath, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - YPSL Leaflets, 1969 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Other US Groups - (SDS, Black Panthers, etc.), 1964-1970 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Civil Rights - periodicals, pamphlets, letters, news articles, 1950s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 9-10)
    - Coalition Politics in New York - proposal, undated (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Commune, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Government Documents, 1950 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - New Left and Old Left, 1917-1964 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Political leadership, Collectivism, Agrarian and other topics, 1968-1970 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Politics in the United States, 1940s-1960s (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Politics in the United States (Yiddish articles by David Shub), 1940, 1964-1969 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Protest in American History, undated (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Village Voice - attached note - Tom Milstein, Mar 23, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - World War Il, 1940s (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - "Young Trade Unionists: Call For Party Equality", 1968, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Young Workers Liberation League (YWLL), 1972 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Irving Howe: Wohlforth's History of American Trotskyism - news articles, letter, publication, 1919-1963 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Irving Howe - articles by and about Howe, 1966-1971 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Tom Kahn - excerpt on "Black Power", 1964-1965 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Lovestone biography, 1940s-1960s (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - McGovern - voting record and open letter, 1950s-1970s (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - David McReynolds - articles from Village Voice, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - PART C: MANUSCRIPTS BY OTHERS (not microfilmed)
    - Reuben Ainsztein - Midstream" - (A Monthly Jewish Review), 1960s (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Jack Barbash - "The Labor Day Movement in the United States", Aug 1957 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Abraham Ben-Shalom' "Stalingrad's Enemies from the1eft", Mar 1943 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Nicholas Berdyaev' "The Metamorphosis of Marxism!' The American Review, Sep 1934 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Alexander Berkman "The Kionstadt Rebellion", 1922 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Franz Borkenau - Ine Threat of Polycentrism", Jul 30, 1956 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Bruno - Critiques of the Transitional program of F.I.(in German), Jul 21, 1938 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - N. Bukharin' "The Theory of Organized Mismanagement"' Pravda, Jun 30, 1929 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - "Capitalism" (unknown author), undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Albert' D. Chang - "Chinese Communism, an Amazing Puzzle", 1952 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Michel Collinet (France), Le Developement de l'opposition Communiste depuis le Zoe Congres de Moscou, 1950s (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Eunice Corfman - "The Bigotry of Liberal Magazines", Jun 12, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Tho Dan - "New Road to a New World" - speech, Feb 1943 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Declaration of the 500, ca.1927 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Milovan Djilas - "Russia's Dangerous New Doctrine of Conquest", ca.1960 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Dissent -' articles on the welfare state and socialism, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Max Eastman - "The Real Situation in Russia", 1927 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - An die Einwort - Socialist Unity Party (E. Germany), ca.1960 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - James T. Farrell - politics, 1940s (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Friends of Soviet Russia - "Soviet Russia", Mar 1, 1922 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Eric Fromm - "Socialist Manifesto and Program", early1960s (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - "Gibt es Sowjet - Imperialismus?" (unkown author), early1940s (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - B.Z. Goldberg - "Travels in the Soviet Union", reprint from Midstream (a monthly Jewish review), Nov 1966 (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - Olive H. Golden - "Administration of the Attorney-General's List of Subversive Organization: The Case of the Workers Party and ISL11, Aug 1962 (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Julian Gorkin - "Indoctrinated Assassins: New Light on Trotsky's Death", 1960s (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - Ted Grant - I'Marxist Theory of the State as Applied to Stalinist State", 1970 (Box 37, Folder 29)
    - Mike Harrington on Socialism, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 30)
    - Bruno Hofer - "Problems of the Working Class", mid1940s (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Sidney Hook - "Report on the International Day Against Dictatorship"; "What's Left of Karl Marx?", 1949 (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
    - "Jerusalem August 1929" - (1968 translation) (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Franz Jung - "Das Tragische Schicksal des Dr. Wilhelm Reich", 1960s (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Bernard Karsh - "The Impact of the Political Left", 1958 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Pia Carena Leonetti - short stories (draft), 1893-1968 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Issac Don Levine - Daily Worker articles, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - George Lichtheim - World Poll-tics 1969" (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Joseph P, Lyford - "Who's Brainwashing Whom?, 1960s (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Herbert Marcuse and Milovan Djilas - "Who is the Revolutionary?", 1960s (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Robert Martinson - "Spain and the Popular Front", 1960s (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Tom Ilstein -"Thoughts on the 1968 Elections", 1969 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Moscow News - supplement to issue 022, 1970 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Jan Ko Wzrin - "Introduction to German Edition of History of Russian Revolution by L.T.", Nov 1959 (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Boris Nikoliesky - "An Eye from Moscow Reports" (Yiddish), Jun 1964 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Dimitry Pospielovsky - "Dogmas Under Attack: A Traveler's Report", 1967 (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Eugene Rabinowitch, ed. - "To.Build or Not to Build", Nov 1961 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Rakovsky - "letter to Valentinov", Aug 2, 1928 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Jack Rader, et.al. - "Superior Court of Renna County Election Code of Phila vs Jack Rader", Oct 1948 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - John Roche "The Uses of American Power", Mar 2, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - Rosdolsky articles, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Alfred Rosmer - John Reed in 1920 (in French), 1927 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - Bayard Rustin - "The Failure of Black Separatism!', a speech, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - Anatole Shub - "From Russia to the Chutzpah", 1972 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - Slavin - "Young Town Labor", "Me Bottom Fifth", 1964 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - Socialist Youth League - "sing:", a songbook, early1940s (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - Boris Souvarine - Esope. 2 issues, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Spartacus - unknown author; in German, 1950s (Box 38, Folder 29-30)
    - Strarkhov - report by Comrade Strakhov, Aug 1928 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Norman Thomas - Has Socialism Any Future?", Aug 1956 (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - Gus Tyler - "The Liberal Crisis", Oct 23, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - Juan Luis Velazquez - Trotsky, Einstein, 1941, 1956 (Box 38, Folder 34)
    - Ludwig Von Mises - Laissez Faire or Dictatorship: Louis Jay Herman - "The Communist Record", late1940s (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Max Ways - "Antitrust in an Era of Federal Change", 1967 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Jack Weber - "The Fetishism of Formulas on Palestine", Nov 1946 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Theodore H. White - "The Making of the President, 1968", 1969 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Wittfogel - articles on China, 1961-1970 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Wohlforth - "What Makes Shachtman Run?", Aug 1957 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Erich Wollenberg - "The Red Army" (in English and German), undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - PART D: MAX SHACHTMAN MANUSCRIPTS AND OTHER NOTES (microfilmed)
    - From the Bolshevik Rev. to the Stalinist State, The Rise of Bureaucratic Collectivism, undated (Box 39A, Folder 1)
    - Booklists, undated (Box 39A, Folder 2)
    - Speech on Bureaucratic Revolution - notes, 1960s (Box 39A, Folder 3)
    - "The Communist International and the National-Colonial Question", 1965 (Box 39A, Folder 4)
    - On the Question of the Congress Socialist Party (India), 1938 (Box 39A, Folder 5)
    - "Ghost of Eugene Duhring" -International News, 1944 (Box 39A, Folder 6)
    - Reply to Comrade Grant (Worker's Party and Fourth International), 1947 (Box 39A, Folder 7)
    - Historia y Principios de la Oposicion de Izquierda (see also: Series I: Left Opposition-Spain), 1933 (Box 39A, Folder 8)
    - Introduction to New International reprint, 1968 (Box 39A, Folder 9)
    - Introduction to Socialist Appeal reprint, 1968 (Box 39A, Folder 10)
    - Introductions for University of Michigan Press, 1962-1967 (Box 39A, Folder 11)
    - An Open Letter to Dean Acheson, May 1951 (Box 39A, Folder 12)
    - Prefacing Remarks to Lenin Testament, 1930s (Box 39A, Folder 13)
    - Reply to the article by Corey, 1940 (Box 39A, Folder 14)
    - Reply to the pamphlet by M.J. Olgin, ca.1935 (Box 39A, Folder 15)
    - Notes on Revolution in Italy - Irving Plazahall, Aug 8, 1943 (Box 39A, Folder 16)
    - "The Russian Oppositions", 1964 (Box 39A, Folder 17)
      Microfilm Reel Number 45
    - "The Situation in the American Opposition: Prospect and Retrospect", 1932 (Box 39A, Folder 18)
    - "Socialist Appeal - An Organ of Rev. Socialism!' (see also: Folder 16), 1968 (Box 39A, Folder 19)
    - Socialist Manifesto and Program notes an Erich Fromm's draft, 1960s (Box 39A, Folder 20)
    - "Comintern's Splinter Movements" comments by R.V. Daniels and M.S, notes, 1964 (Box 39A, Folder 21)
    - Stalinism. - notes, 1943-1958 (Box 39A, Folder 22)
    - Discussion of State Capitalism, undated (Box 39A, Folder 23)
    - Theses on Decline of SP notes, ca.. (Box 39A, Folder 24)
    - M.S. article for Survey"1939 Whither Russia", 1962 (Box 39A, Folder 25)
    - (reprint) "1939 Whither Russia: Trotsky and his Critics" (Box 39A, Folder 26)
    - Notes on Russian Question, 1900s-1940s (Box 40, Folder 1-4)
      Microfilm Reel Number 45 (Reel 46 begins with folder 8)
    - List of names (German) who showed up in Moscow in the 1930's, ca.1930 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Microfilm Reel Number 46
    - M.S. notes - quotes, 1915-1920s, 1940s (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Some points from Party Publications, 1930s (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Notes on the Organization of his records, 1930-1940 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - E. Clippings, articles about Max Shachtman (not microfilmed).
    - Hoover Institution: conference, Oct 5, 1964-Oct 11, 1964 (Box 40A, Folder 1)
    - Interview by Albert Meyer, 1972 (Box 40A, Folder 2)
    - Leaflets, clippings of M.S. speaking engagements, 1950s-1960s (Box 40A, Folder 3)
    - Leaflets, and tour announcements about M.S., 1960s-1970s (Box 40A, Folder 4)
    - About Max Shachtman - clippings, articles, 1900-1961 (Box 40A, Folder 5)
    - Shub, David; MacDonald, Dwight - correspondence, Jan 1950 (Box 40A, Folder 6)
- Series V: International bulletins, periodicals, and other documents
  - PART A: LEFT OPPOSITION BULLETINS
    - International Information of the Communist. Opposition - (in English), May 1930-Aug 1930 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Bulletin International(in French), Aug 1930-Jun 1932 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Bulletin of the Opposition(in Russian), 1931-1939 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Microfilm Reel Number 47
    - International Bulletin of the Comnnist Left Opposition(in English), Feb 1931-Jul 1931 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Bolletino Interno della Frazione di Sinistra(in Italian), Feb 1931-May 1932 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Bulletin de la Gauche Communiste(in French), Apr 1931-Jun 1931 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Bolletino de L'opposizione P.C.I.(in Italian), Apr 1931-Feb 1933 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      Microfilm Reel Number 48
    - Bulletin de L'opposizion communiste- Bruxelles (in French), Jun 1931-Jul 1931 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Mitteilungsblatt- Left Oppostion of the KPD - KPD (Communist Party of Germany) (in German) "For Members Only", Jun 1931-Feb 1933 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Bulletin Interieur(in French), Aug 1931-Sep 1931 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Bulletin d'Information de la Fraction de Gauche Italienne(in Prench), Aug 1931-Mar 1932 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      Microfilm Reel Number 49
    - Bulletin International de L'opposition communiste de Gauche(in French), Nov 1931 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Internationales Bulletin(in German), Nov 1931-Aug 1932 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Bulletin de la Lique des Communistes Internationalistes(in French), Mar 1932-Feb 1939 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      Microfilm Reel Number 50
    - Fraction de Gauche du Parti Communiste Italien(in French), Jul 1932 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Bulletin de La Fraction de Gauche(opposition) (in French), Aug 1932-Oct 1932 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Bulletin International(in French), Feb 1933-Jul 1933 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Pour la Renaissance Communiste (in French), Feb 17, 1933 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Bulletin D'Information de la Ligue Communiste(in French), Mar 1933-Oct 1935 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Informationsdienst-Inte-mationale Kommuniste Deutschlands(LO) - in German, Sep 1933-Mar 1936 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      Microfilm Reel Number 51
    - For Discussion - Internal Bulletin Communist League ILO-BL(in English), Oct 1933 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Nachrichten der Linksopposition- Austria (in German), Sep 1933-Oct 1933 (Box 42, Folder 10)